Guide to the Edward E. Smuts Papers, 1945-1981 AIS.2012.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Edward E. Smuts Papers
1945-1981
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Smuts, Edward E.
AIS.2012.07
27 Linear Feet
The Edward E. Smuts Papers document the professional career and involvement of Ed Smuts with urban planning in Pittsburgh and the surrounding area. Smuts served as the president of the Regional Industrial Development Consultants (RIDC) from 1957-1959 and deputy director for the City Planning and Development of Pittsburgh from 1965-1970; he owned his own urban consulting firm, Urban Development Consultants Incorporated, from 1960-1984.
Biography
Edward E. Smuts was born October 25, 1924. He married Marjorie Palmer and had six children (Peter, Thomas, Shannon, Christian, Matthew and Daniel). Throughout his life, Smuts was active in many associations, including the American Institute of Planners, Pittsburgh Chapter of American Society for Public Administration, American Society of Planning Officials, and Pittsburgh History & Landmarks Foundation.
Smuts earned his B.A. from Carnegie Institute of Technology in 1946. After earning his master's degree in Business Administration from Harvard Univeristy, Smuts returned to Pittsburgh to start his career in the urban planning. His first job was with the Pennsylvania Economy League of Pittsburgh. In 1957 Smuts took the position as president of Regional Industrial Development Cooperation (RIDC). He left RIDC in 1959 to become an independent planning consultant.
Smuts established Urban Development Consultants Incorporated and served as president from 1960-1965. His company performed consulting and market research studies of the Pittsburgh area. Some of these research studies included, mass transportation, air pollution, and business development sites. From 1965-1970 he served as deputy director of City Planning and Development in Pittsburgh. As deputy director Smuts took action in projects to improve transportation, parking, business development, and university expansion. Some of these projects were Craig Street project, Carnegie Mellon University, and Greenway projects around Pittsburgh.
In 1970 Smuts returned to Urban Development Consultants, Inc. During his career as president of his consulting form, Smuts contributed to diverse development projects around the Pittsburgh and Allegheny County area.
Edward Smuts died on February 2, 1984 in Pittsburgh.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marjorie Palmer Smuts on November 5, 2012.
Scope and Content Notes
The Edward E. Smuts Papers document the various professional positions he held in the capacity of an urban planner in the Pittsburgh area. The papers include business material, correspondence, meeting notes, project agendas, agreements between organizations, lease agreements, financial reports, data surveys, statistics, press releases, published reports, studies, and proposals. The topics covered by the papers include urban planning, urban redevelopment, greenway projects, traffic planning, university development, hospital ventures, and county planning in Southwestern Pennsylvania.
Related Material
Allegheny Conference on Community Development Collection, 1944-1993, AIS.1973.04, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania Records, 1971-1987, AIS.1987.02, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Pennsylvania Economy League Records, AIS.1978.06, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Urban League of Pittsburgh Records, 1915-1963, AIS.1981.11, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Previous Citation
Edward E. Smuts Papers, 1945-1981, AIS.2012.07, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Department of City Planning and Development
Series II. Pennsylvania Economy League
Series III. Personal
Series IV. Professional Associations
Series V. Regional Industrial Development Corporation
Series VI. Related Professional Materials
Series VII. Urban Development Consultations, Inc.
Series VIII. Urban Redevelopment Authority
North Side (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.); Urban renewal -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Landscape architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Landscape design -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Health services administration -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Health planning -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Medical policy -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Economic development -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Allegheny County (Pa.); Transportation; Social action; Health and medicine; Government; Environment; Business and Industry; Homewood (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Oakland (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Pennsylvania Economy League; Pittsburgh (Pa.). Department of City Planning; Smuts, Edward E.; Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania; Urban Development Consultants, Inc; Regional Industrial Development Corporation of Southwestern Pennsylvania
- Department of City Planning, 1954-1979; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series covers the period that Smuts was the of Deputy Director of City Planning of Pittsburgh (1965-1970) and beyond. Materials document City Planning projects and program and include agreements, reports, and correspodence.
  - Topical Folders, 1957-1979; 1.
    This subseries represents various projects and programs of the Department of City Planning. Materials contained in these folders include memorandum of projects, agendas, press release, agreements, reference materials, project proposals, financial/expenditures reports, photographs, presentation reports, area surveys, and multiple forms of communications.
    - Action-Housing, Inc., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Action-Housing, Inc. - Reports, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Action-Housing, Inc. - District Liaison - Neighborhood Programs, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aerial Photography, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny County Planning Commission, unknown (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Allegheny Housing Rehabilitation Corporation (AHRCO), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American Institute of Architects and Urban American Inc. Design Concept Seminar, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - American Institute of Planners - Finance Historical & Reference, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Society for Public Administration (ASPA), 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Society for Public Administration (ASPA) - Urban Intern Program, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - American Society of Planning Officials, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - ARA Project - Sixth Empire Fund, Inc., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Armour and Company, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Armstrong Cork Company, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Automobile Deal Development, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Binswager Corporation, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Board of Education - Education Park, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Business and Urban Problems, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Center Business District (Center 1), 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21-25)
    - City Business District - Library Avenue-Allegheny River Action Area, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - City Information System – City Wide -Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - City of Pittsburgh – Neighborhood – Commercial Improvement Program – General, unknown (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - City Service Guide, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Community Facilities, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Community Renewal Plan (CRP): Open Space, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    - Comprehensive Planning and Programming, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Downtown Development Plan, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Art Commission, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Economic Development Plan, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Environmental Nuisance Control, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Environmentally Sensitive/Predominately Vacant: City of Pittsburgh, 1969-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Exchange Fund Inc. – Director's Meeting and Correspondents, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Filtration Site, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
    - Golden Triangle Association, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Herrs Island Project, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Housing Project, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Housing Program, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Housing Program R-5 Target Area, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Housing Program Relocation, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Housing Planning Reference Book, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Hourly Work Schedule, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Industrial Renewal and Development Projects Follow-Up, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - J. H. Matthews and Co., 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Joint Development – S1 Saw Mill Run- Design Concept Team, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Land Use Control, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Legislation Program, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mauro, John T. - Speech American Society of Military Engineers, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mayor's Office, 1968-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N2 – Lower Northside, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - N3 – Federal Anderson, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Northside Anderson – East State Renewal Project, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Parking, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Parking Ordinances, 1965-1976 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Parks and Recreation, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania – Overall Company, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Pennsylvania – State Planning Board, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Point Bridges & Pedestrian Paths, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Population Forecasts – Pittsburgh, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Projects, Priorities, and Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Port Authority of Allegheny County – Transit Division Planning Department, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Public Action to Hold Existing Industries, unknown (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Public Relations, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Public Safety Traffic Planning, 1968-1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Public Works, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Rapid Transit Program, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
    - Rapid Transit Study, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Recreation Facility and Program, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Regional Economic Development Institute - Incorporated, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Regional Planning Association - Annual Meeting, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Riverfront Program, 1958-1969 (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
    - Rockwell Manufacturing Company, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Seldom Seen Program, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Sharon Project, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Slide Presentation, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission (SPRPC), 1965-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - SPRPC - Open Space Task Forces, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - SPRPC-Work Program, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - State Highway, 1967-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Strip District – Interview/Recon, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Taber Follow-Up, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Transportation Thoroughfare Improvement Program – Index, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Tranist - Center City Transportation Project, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Transit - Center City - Wotsit Pitch, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Transit - Core Penetration - Final Analysis, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Transit - Core Penetration - Station Design, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Transit - General, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Transit – National Transportation Center, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Transit - PAT property Acquisition – RT, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Transit – Pittsburgh Transit-Historical, 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Transit – Pole Removal Program, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Transit - Regional Designs, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Transit 4 Transit Program Follow-Up, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Transit US Steel Penetration, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Transit, Mass & Rapid – Core, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Transit, Mass & Rapid – Center Business District Planning- Distribution, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Transit, Mass & Rapid – Miscellaneous, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Transit, Mass, & Rapid - Reference, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Westinghouse – Information Systems Project, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Zoning Ordinance of Pittsburgh, 1968-1979 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Reports, Studies, and Proposals, 1954-1979; 2.
    This subseries contains reports, studies, and proposals on City Planning project such as, North side redevelopment, highways and transportation, stadiums, Golden Triangle redevelopment, housing, Homewood-Brushton improvements and more.
    - "North Side Study", April 1954 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "State Highway Policies and Practices in Pennsylvania: An Appraisal by the Automotive Safety Foundation", August 1958 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Report on Proposed New Stadium", September 1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Pittsburgh Pennsylvania Chateau Street West Marketability Analysis", July 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Planning Report Stage One Chartiers Valley Industrial Study Area", April 1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "1961 Annual Report: A City Rebuilds", May 1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Freeways in the Urban Setting: The Hershey Conference", June 1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Pittsburgh Area Transportation Study: Volume 2 Forecasts and Plans", February 1963 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Data Processing and Simulation Techniques", October 1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "1962-1963 Community Renewal Program: A City Rebuilds", October 1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Golden Triangle Study: Future Circulation", February 1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "A Concept for Personnel Distribution and Circulation in a City Central Core", June 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Lower Northside: Basic Conditions Reports", December 1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "Community Renewal Project Progress Report: Simulation Model Number 5", January 1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "State of the Region Project: Work Element 5: A Prospectus for the Study of Leadership in Southwestern Pennsylvania", July 1964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "A Plan and Program for Industrial Development in Pittsburgh", 1965 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "Study Design: Drainage Basins and Flood Plains Sanitary Sewerage Water Supply and Service Project No. Penna. P-103", August 1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "Study Design Transportation - Air Project No. Penna. P-103 Contract No. Penna. P-103(G)", September 1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "Highways and Urban Development: Report on the Second National Conference", November 1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "1966 Work Program" (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Housing Report Summary City of Pittsburgh", April 1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "Feasibility Report Filling the Herrs Island Back Channel for Future Land Development", August 1967 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "What it Takes to Build a City of Housing Opportunities", May-June 1967 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Planning Programming Budgeting for City, State, County Objectivies", April 1967 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Auto Pound Study", April 1967 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Information Systems Laboratory: Capabilities and Experiences in Public Systems", June 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "Homewood Brushton Neighborhood Improvement Program", March 1968 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Manchester Basic Conditions Report", January 1968 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - "Tax Delinquent Property Transfer Program Progress Report", April 1968 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "City of Pittsburgh Change in the Housing Inventory 1960-1968", August 1968 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "1967-1968 Work Program", 1969 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "Westinghouse - Information System Department Organization Plan: Agreement No. 19170, Report No. 1", May 1969 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - "Westinghouse - Preliminary Organization and Staffing Plan: Agreement No. 9247, Report No.1", April 1969 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - "Westinghouse - Information System Office Recruitment Plan: Agreement No. 19170, Report No. 2", July 1969 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - "Westinghouse - A Study Report Covering: City of Pittsburgh Information System Study: Findings and Recommendations for a Central Information Processing Facility", February 1969 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - "Westinghouse - Information System Project System Description: Agreement No. 19170, Report No.3", August 1969 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - "Westinghouse Reports 1969" (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - "A Profile of the Residents of Sheraden Park: Comprehensive Planning and Programming Division", April 1969 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - "Herr's Island Study: A Recreation Island for Pittsburgh and Allegheny County", January 1969 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - "The Black Population and its Housing: A Social and Economic Profile of The Black Community in the Pittsburgh Metropolitan Area", May 1969 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - "Message of the Mayor", January 1969 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - "A Profile of the Residents of Pennley Park: Comprehensive Planning and Programming Division", June 1969 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - "Clifton Park Basic Conditions Report", September 1969 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - "City of Pittsburgh Changes in the Housing Inventory 1960-1968", January 1969 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - "Anderson-Chestnut Land Assembly Program for Highways and Riverside Imporvement", February 1970 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - "Sewage System: Plan and Program City of Pittsbrugh", January, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - "A Development and Renewal Program for Pittsburgh: Summary Documentation", February 1970 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - "London Borough of Haringey Seven Sisters Study: Project Submission", September 1970 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - "Lower North Side District Plan", May 1970 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - "Golden Triangle Street Program 1968-1973", February 1968 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Pennsylvania Economy League, 1951-1969; II.
  This series highlights Smuts' work with the Pennsylvania Economy League. Some of the folders contain in-depth reports and information about counties in southwestern Pennsylvania, including field reports, contacts, industrial surveys, pamphlets, demographics, and planning programs.
  - County-Armstrong, 1951-1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - County-Butler, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - County-Fayette, 1954-1958 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - County-Westmoreland, 1953-1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Nuisance Control - Air Pollution, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Nuisance Control - Litter, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Financing the Civic Auditorium", January 1956 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "A More Effective Industrial Development Program for the Pittsburgh Region", November 1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "A More Effective Industrial Development Program for the Pittsburgh Region – Appendices", 1954 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Recommended Program and Staffing of the Pennsylvania Department of Commerce", 1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Personal, 1953-1980; III.
  The Personal series contains Smuts' correspondence with local businesses, professional associations, and personal acquaintances. It also includes materials related to voter registration drives in Allegheny County. Other folders include materials concerning his marriage to Marjorie Palmer and her business, Marj Palmer Associates.
  - Allegheny County Government, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Awards, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 14-18)
  - Daily Calendar, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Litchfield Park, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Marjorie Ann Palmer Smuts, 1953-1980 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Marj Palmer Associates, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Professional Associations, 1945-1976; IV.
  This series covers the multitude of professional and personal associations that Smuts was involved with throughout his life. It contains newsletters, by-laws, correspondence, and speeches. Of special note are the files on the Pittsburgh History & Landmarks Foundation, which includes flyers, memorandums, correspondence, handwritten notes, and newsletters. Smuts also taught Urban Studies classes at both Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) and the University of Pittsburgh; this folder contains the syllabus, correspondence, list of textbooks, presentation slides and notes. Smuts was also actively involved with the CMU Alumni Association, which is documented in a single folder of photographs, committee reports, executive board meeting notes, pamphlets, and newspaper clippings.
  - American Conservatory Theater Foundation, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - American Institute of Planners, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 24-27)
  - American Society for Public Administration, 1956-1965 (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
  - ASPEN Design Confrence, unknown (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Committee for Industrial Development, 1945-1954 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Constitutional Revision Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Courses - University of Pittsburgh and CMU, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - CMU Alumni Association, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5-8)
  - Foundation Data, 1953-1957 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Mountain Club, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - National Association of Housing & Redevelopment Officials, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania Planning Association, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pittsburgh History & Landmarks Foundations, 1962-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
- Regional Industrial Development Corporation (RIDC), 1949-1977; V.
  This series includes documentation on projects of the Regional Industrial Development Corporation (RIDC) during the Smuts' tenure as its president (1957-1959) and beyond. This series also includes a significant amount of promotional material compiled on Pittsburgh area companies and includes industrial statistics for the area.
  - Topical Folders, 1949-1964; 1.
    This subseries consists of subject folders related to various projects and reference material of the RIDC. Folders reflect daily operations and business relationships, board meeting minutes, agenda, notices, correspondence, press releases, copies of newspaper articles, and indexes.
    - Boston Economic Study Committee, 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Chateau Street West, 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Chartiers Basin Survey 1958 Conclusions (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Committee for Economic Development (CED), 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Counties, 1955-1959 (Box 7, Folder 21-24)
    - Economic Development – State Program, 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Filing Index, unknown (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Future Programs, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Government Improvement Ideas, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Office, Pennsylvania, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Area Renewal Program, Industrial Standards (Idea Book), 1954-1958 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Industrial Clusters, Pittsburgh Region, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Industrial Development Fund, 1959-1962 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Interview Kit, unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Labor Management Relations, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Laurel Highlands Project, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Little, Arthur D. Inc., 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Maps, 1951-1959 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, Agenda, and Notices, RIDC Board Meetings, 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Mon-Yough Conference on Community Development, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 14)